{
    "id": "a9062b9032ea4d56846bbdfa8b341b89",
    "title": "Subordinating conjunctions",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "b12f5d1810864e2397ea01086e6027c5",
            "title": "Subordinating Conjunctions",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I don’t know …………………… he is innocent.",
                    "description": "We use whether to introduce indirect yes/no questions.",
                    "answers": [
                        "that",
                        "weather",
                        "whether"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………………. she will come I am not sure at the moment.",
                    "description": "When an indirect question is fronted, we use whether, not if.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Whether",
                        "If",
                        "That"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I asked …………………….. she had met me before.",
                    "description": "Both whether and if can be used to introduce indirect yes/no questions.",
                    "answers": [
                        "whether",
                        "if",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the closet ………………………. she keeps her things.",
                    "description": "We need a place word here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "where",
                        "that",
                        "which"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The consequence of his stupidity was ……………………….. he soon lost his money.",
                    "description": "That is merely a connector. When we split the sentence into two clauses, we get:\r\nHe soon lost his money.\r\nIt was the consequence of his stupidity.\r\nWe can combine them with that.\r\n",
                    "answers": [
                        "that",
                        "which",
                        "what"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is beautiful. She is equally intelligent. That means she is as beautiful as ………………..",
                    "description": "Both clauses have the same pattern in this structure.",
                    "answers": [
                        "intelligent",
                        "is intelligent",
                        "she is intelligent"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "A cottager and his wife had a hen …………………….. laid a golden egg every day.",
                    "description": "Both that and which can be used to refer to animals, birds or things.",
                    "answers": [
                        "which",
                        "that",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ran so quickly ……………………… he soon overtook me.",
                    "description": "The conjunction so…that… is used to indicate ideas such as effect or purpose.",
                    "answers": [
                        "that",
                        "when",
                        "for"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He spoke in ……………………… a low voice that nobody could hear him.",
                    "description": "We use such before 'adjective + noun'. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "so",
                        "very",
                        "such"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Tell me what …………………………. done?",
                    "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have you",
                        "you have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………….. you are drunk aggravates your offence.",
                    "description": "That-clauses are not normally used alone as subjects. They are often introduced by the expression ‘the fact’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Fact",
                        "The fact",
                        "The fact that"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "They paid no attention to ………………………. she was depressed.",
                    "description": "That-clauses after prepositions are introduced by ‘the fact’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "fact",
                        "fact that",
                        "the fact that"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}